Nov. 2015 - present

http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

Personal Statement

My industry experience has exposed me to many fun technologies, fueling my interests in cryptography, probabilistic programming, and languages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new programming language or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has granted me strong communication skills, and solid background. See my project details at http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com.

Language Experience :

* Python Julia Figaro BTEX Scala Ada С

Work Experience

- Contractor/Consultant Independent

C&W Energy

Authored educational material on light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a memoizing database-interface for caching computationally expensive operations

ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis June 2016

PDXCodeGuild Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

- Research Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015 Galois Inc.

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Languages Used: Ada, C++, Scheme, R

Neato Projects

Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Course Dating a Band - Lyrics Release Date Classifier Splingr - Shamir Secret QR Sharing Probabilistic-Program Profiler and Evaluator Harness Probabilistic WiFi Geolocation Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Liars Dice Game Server

sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python javascript, Python Python SLURM, PonyORM, Python Figaro, Scala, Javascript Hadoop, Python Erlang, Sagemath R, Perl Ada

С

Education

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Non-Matriculated (Masters) 2016 - present

Courses :

Analysis of Sequences
Univariate Statistical Analysis

Statistical Methods Digital Signal Processing

Western Washington University

Computer Science BS Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Computer Science

Core Coursework :

Unix Software Development
Windows Software Development
Operating Systems
Analysis/Design of Algorithms
Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures

Formal Languages/Automata
Programming Languages
Concurrent Programming
Computer Organization I/II
Object-Oriented Programming in C++

Elective Coursework :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming Computer Graphics Computer Architecture
Number Theory
Elementary Real Analysis
Ordinary Differential Equations
Linear Algebra I/II
Abstract Algebra

Honors and Related Activities

Pacific Rim Regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (Fourth Place) - March 2012

Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Meritorious Winner) - Top 10% - Feb. 2012

Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Honorable Mention) - Top 30% - Feb. 2011